<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Irreverent Pixel Feats</title>
        <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com</link>
        <description><![CDATA[Thoughts on Indie Game Dev, Software Engineering, Tech Culture, etc...]]></description>
        <atom:link href="http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/rss.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>Ecology</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/development/2018-07-21-ecology.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ecology</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> Projects as Code
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2018-07-21" pubdate data-updated="true">July 21, 2018</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 8 mins
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/development.html">development</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/tags/ecology.html">ecology</a>, <a href="/tags/productivity.html">productivity</a>, <a href="/tags/projects-as-code.html">projects-as-code</a>
</div>


<p>Well, its been a while in between posts here, and we had said we would be posting more frequently.</p>
<p>So, we’re still working on it…</p>
<!-- more -->
<h2 id="background-context">Background Context</h2>
<p>Hopefully its clear from the Philosophy that we published (but haven’t re-worded for clarity yet :( ) that at Irreverent, we aren’t just concerned with making games, we are interested in making a culture and workplace where we enjoy making games.</p>
<p>That means that even if we think it slows down production of our games (even our very first one…), but will make the experience of making games (or other things) a lot more enjoyable for us, we’ll do it.</p>
<p>If you look at our GitHub account, its pretty clear that we go with the “multi-repo” approach, as opposed to the “mono-repo” approach. Some companies use the multi-repo approach for their open source projects, and have a mono-repo internally, internally we also operate with multi-repos.</p>
<p>We do this because, to us, it embodies the FP (Functional Programming) spirit a little more. When we program in the small, FP lets us focus on individual functions a lot of the time, without having to worry about grand effects on mutable state etc… . We like having that feeling when working on projects too, hence we like each repo having a small self-contained focus. As close as we can get anyway.</p>
<p>Anyway, multi/mono repos have nothing to do with FP, just saying, one of the things FP delivers, is something we’d like to be delivered by our “project structure paradigm/model” as well.</p>
<p>Again because of that property, we feel like multi-repos enforces a more modular approach. Again though, mono-repos don’t preclude a modular approach, neither is a clear winner, ultimately what it comes down to which one feels better to you, and which weaknesses you want to invest time in compensating for, long CI build times for mono-repos, or messy integrations with multi-repos, etc…</p>
<p>Anyway this isn’t a “multi repo vs mono repo” post, this is just for context, theres a more detailed post (by someone else) on comparing the pros and cons of each approach <a href="http://gigamonkeys.com/mono-vs-multi">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="so-ecology">So, Ecology?</h2>
<p>So that brings us to the point of this post, we are using the multi-repo approach and are looking at compensating for the problems that multi-repos have compared to the mono-repo approach.</p>
<p>This is the focus of the <a href="https://github.com/irreverent-pixel-feats/ecology"><code>ecology</code></a> project we open sourced last week.</p>
<p>Here are some explicit specific goals, but its not limited to these:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reduce the overhead of setting up new repos. This is one of the most obvious draw backs of using multiple repos, with a mono repo you are setting up one repo and its CI process and its done, with multi-repos you will be creating many, and it will be a regular activity. Ecology automates this process.</li>
<li>Reduce the amount of time spent maintaining CI etc… for these projects.
<ul>
<li>Even when you aren’t creating new projects, you have to maintain the ones you already got
<ul>
<li>These days with “CI as a service” like TravisCI, CircleCI, Bitbucket Pipelines and etc… there is a lot of config that is duplicated in each of the projects.</li>
<li>Ecology lets you put this in one place (AWS SSM Parameter Store) and distribute it out to the CI platform.</li>
<li>If you are migrating from one CIaaS platform to another, using Ecology as a library might help you script a migration process in Haskell.</li>
<li>Or it can help you maintain some of your projects in one platform with some in the other during the transition phase.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Using the multi-repo approach means you have smaller projects in bite sized portions for newcomers to digest, without having to ignore the noise of the other projects in a mono-repo.
<ul>
<li>Ecology seeks to help track in a rudimentary way what team members are familiar with what projects eventually going so far as to suggest what project your next team knowledge sharing session should focus on.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>It still requires some documentation, and rather than start from the “easily implement this by calling the one function we provide” which offers convenience, but lacks flexibility, we have started with the “combine these functions to do what you want” approach, and we’ll work towards <em>also</em> providing a single function that does what we think is the least restrictive default. Once we figure that out.</p>
<p>So when you want to create a new project (or multiple projects that combine to form a system):</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Raise a PR on your ecology project that adds the declaration of your project to the overall list of projects.</li>
<li>Your team mates can discuss whether:
<ul>
<li>The project is necessary</li>
<li>Is named appropriately</li>
<li>Is tagged appropriately</li>
<li>Is configured correctly</li>
</ul></li>
<li>If the project is deemed unnecessary, decline the PR, otherwise once you merge it, ecology will:
<ul>
<li>Create the repositories on Bitbucket/GitHub
<ul>
<li>Perform any additional config (e.g. setting user group privileges)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Pull down the appropriate template and bootstrap it with the appropriate project details.</li>
<li>Add any CI config to the repo (e.g. <code>bitbucket-pipelines.yaml</code> or <code>.travis.yaml</code>)</li>
<li>Perform cloud side CI config (e.g. activate bitbucket pipelines, add SSH keys, set environment variables)</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s an example of what a project that you add might look like:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1"><pre class="sourceCode haskell"><code class="sourceCode haskell"><a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-1" data-line-number="1"><span class="ot">exampleProject ::</span> <span class="dt">IrreverentEcologyProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-2" data-line-number="2">exampleProject <span class="fu">=</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-3" data-line-number="3">  <span class="kw">let</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-4" data-line-number="4"><span class="ot">    ciVars ::</span> [<span class="dt">EcologyEnvironmentPair</span>]</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-5" data-line-number="5">    ciVars <span class="fu">=</span> [</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-6" data-line-number="6">        <span class="dt">EcologyEnvironmentPair</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-7" data-line-number="7">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableName</span> <span class="st">&quot;PARAMFOO&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-8" data-line-number="8">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableReferenceValue</span> <span class="st">&quot;common/PARAMFOO&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-9" data-line-number="9">      , <span class="dt">EcologyEnvironmentPair</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-10" data-line-number="10">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableName</span> <span class="st">&quot;PARAMBAR&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-11" data-line-number="11">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableReferenceValue</span> <span class="st">&quot;common/PARAMBAR&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-12" data-line-number="12">      , <span class="dt">EcologyEnvironmentPair</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-13" data-line-number="13">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableName</span> <span class="st">&quot;PARAMBAR3&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-14" data-line-number="14">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableReferenceValue</span> <span class="st">&quot;common/PARAMBAR3&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-15" data-line-number="15">      , <span class="dt">EcologyEnvironmentPair</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-16" data-line-number="16">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableName</span> <span class="st">&quot;PARAMOPEN&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-17" data-line-number="17">          (<span class="dt">EnvironmentVariableValue</span> <span class="st">&quot;In the repo&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-18" data-line-number="18">      ]</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-19" data-line-number="19">  <span class="kw">in</span> <span class="dt">EcologyProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-20" data-line-number="20">    (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectName</span> <span class="st">&quot;ecology-test&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-21" data-line-number="21">    <span class="dt">BitbucketGitPlatform</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-22" data-line-number="22">    (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectDescription</span> <span class="st">&quot;A test repo for ecology to create&quot;</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-23" data-line-number="23">    <span class="dt">I.HaskellProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-24" data-line-number="24">    (pure <span class="dt">I.DevProject</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-25" data-line-number="25">    <span class="dt">ExperimentalStatus</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-26" data-line-number="26">    []</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-27" data-line-number="27">    (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectCI</span> <span class="dt">BitbucketPipelines</span> <span class="fu">$</span> awsCreds <span class="fu">&lt;&gt;</span> ciVars)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-28" data-line-number="28">    <span class="dt">EcologyPrivate</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-29" data-line-number="29">    (<span class="dt">EcologyTag</span> <span class="fu">&lt;$&gt;</span> [<span class="st">&quot;haskell&quot;</span>])</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-30" data-line-number="30">    (<span class="dt">Username</span> <span class="fu">&lt;$&gt;</span> [<span class="st">&quot;domdere&quot;</span>])</a></code></pre></div>
<p>The definition of <code>EcologyProject</code> is <a href="https://github.com/irreverent-pixel-feats/ecology/blob/master/ecology-core/src/Irreverent/Ecology/Core/Data.hs#L328-L340">here</a></p>
<p>And because you are writing this in haskell code, if there are repetitive patterns you see come up, you can write functions to simplify those instances, for example:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2"><pre class="sourceCode haskell"><code class="sourceCode haskell"><a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-1" data-line-number="1">haskellProject</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-2" data-line-number="2"><span class="ot">  ::</span> <span class="dt">T.Text</span> <span class="co">-- ^ Name</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-3" data-line-number="3">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> <span class="dt">T.Text</span>  <span class="co">-- ^ Description</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-4" data-line-number="4">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> <span class="dt">I.IrreverentGitPlatform</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-5" data-line-number="5">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> <span class="dt">I.IrreverentProjectCategory</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-6" data-line-number="6">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> [<span class="dt">T.Text</span>] <span class="co">-- ^ Tags</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-7" data-line-number="7">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> [<span class="dt">T.Text</span>] <span class="co">-- ^ Experts</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-8" data-line-number="8">  <span class="ot">-&gt;</span> <span class="dt">IrreverentEcologyProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-9" data-line-number="9">haskellProject name desc plat cat tags&#39; experts&#39; <span class="fu">=</span> <span class="dt">EcologyProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-10" data-line-number="10">  (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectName</span> name)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-11" data-line-number="11">  plat</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-12" data-line-number="12">  (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectDescription</span> desc)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-13" data-line-number="13">  <span class="dt">I.HaskellProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-14" data-line-number="14">  (pure cat)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-15" data-line-number="15">  <span class="dt">ExperimentalStatus</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-16" data-line-number="16">  []</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-17" data-line-number="17">  (<span class="dt">EcologyProjectCI</span> <span class="dt">NoCI</span> [])</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-18" data-line-number="18">  <span class="dt">EcologyPrivate</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-19" data-line-number="19">  (<span class="dt">EcologyTag</span> <span class="fu">&lt;$&gt;</span> tags&#39;)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-20" data-line-number="20">  (<span class="dt">Username</span> <span class="fu">&lt;$&gt;</span> experts&#39;)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-21" data-line-number="21"></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-22" data-line-number="22"><span class="co">-- A simpler more concise project expression</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-23" data-line-number="23"><span class="ot">ecologyExtras ::</span> <span class="dt">IrreverentEcologyProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-24" data-line-number="24">ecologyExtras <span class="fu">=</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-25" data-line-number="25">  <span class="st">&quot;ecology-extras&quot;</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-26" data-line-number="26">  <span class="st">&quot;Additional extras for writing ecology APIs&quot;</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-27" data-line-number="27">  <span class="dt">BitbucketGitPlatform</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-28" data-line-number="28">  <span class="dt">I.ProductivityProject</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-29" data-line-number="29">  [<span class="st">&quot;ecology&quot;</span>, <span class="st">&quot;projects&quot;</span>, <span class="st">&quot;projects-as-code&quot;</span>]</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-30" data-line-number="30">  [<span class="st">&quot;domdere&quot;</span>]</a></code></pre></div>
<p>So to us, this is better than JSON or YAML. We’d be interested to see if we could switch to processing S-expressions though…</p>
<p>So unless your project requires other integrations (e.g. a DockerHub repo being created) you should have a new repo, with build configuration in it, empty test-suites, and a green CI build, i.e you should be ready to go and start writing code. Its still not instantaneous, but we find its not enough to break the flow yet.</p>
<p>Maybe one day we will add an API allowing you to specify additional things to setup, like DockerHub repos and etc… but we might wait until we have got the Repo and CI experience nicely ironed out before that.</p>
<h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2>
<p>In addition to working towards solving the problems described above, we are experiencing other benefits.</p>
<ul>
<li>Obviously its saved us a lot of time.</li>
<li>The boring menial work that ecology automates is replaced with a streamlined collaboration process to determine whether the project should exist or not. This is a great time to insert a “collaboration point” as people with more domain experience for that particular concept get a chance to speak up if they think a wheel is being re-invented unnecessarily. And they can do this without disrupting the flow of the person who wants to start the project (provided you handle the PR promptly and rein in discussion).
<ul>
<li>Diversity and inclusivity is a big thing to us. Experienced people working with younger or less experienced people often get frustrated when they don’t get a chance to avoid problems they can see down the road, while less experienced people are more keen to just rush ahead.
<ul>
<li>Its not good or bad, it just is, less experienced people push forward while experienced people can suffer from analysis paralysis.</li>
<li>Culture wise what we aim to achieve with ecology is to leverage Diversity in age/experience/skill profile.
<ul>
<li>We want engineers to stop for a second to get the OK from team mates that might have more domain experience, before ecology speeds them forward again by quickly setting everything up for the engineer to do what they are excited about doing.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>We’re hoping this would be great for when we try to tackle Ludum Game Dares, Adventure Game Jams and other such things.
<ul>
<li>Setting up new repos and CI for them is a real pain, and can make the time constraints very stressful. Game Jams are always stressful, but fun at the same time, but for us this is usually the difference between fun and not fun.</li>
<li>So often what you do is go without CI, and but then you risk winding up with a stressful crunch period just before the deadline trying to get a working build. Obviously YMMV, but thats us.</li>
<li>With ecology, we look forward to just having it all there. I’m sure, like the air we breathe, we’ll come to take that for granted.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-future">The Future</h2>
<p>Theres a lot more we can do with that data.</p>
<p>I think we’ll always want to declare the projects in “code” in a language like Haskell (i.e not JSON/YAML/ TOML/etc…), so that we can define functions for repetitive patterns.</p>
<p>This will in general be necessary for performing mass migrations on repos of various kinds.</p>
<p>Ecology would be useful for any scenario where would want to iterate over a bunch of similar projects.</p>
<p>To support this we will likely add a feature to help iterate over projects with certain tags so you can perform some operations en masse.</p>
<p>While we want to keep defining projects in Haskell rather than JSON, it will probably be nice to serialise the list into JSON as part of the sync process and store it somewhere. That way we can write a generic slack bot or something that can perform useful queries and do useful tasks using that data.</p>
<p>I can see that data be coming in handy very much, for instance, whenever you want to upgrade your Haskell compiler, you can add that new target to all your Haskell CI builds very quickly and get a result back quickly to see if such a move breaks any of your projects.</p>
<p>So there is a lot that can be done with it, we’ll be very excited to see where it goes.</p>
<h2 id="see-also">See Also</h2>
<ul>
<li>This is an extension of something the engineering team at Ambiata had done, see their open source version at <a href="https://github.com/ambiata/anatomy"><code>ambiata/anatomy</code></a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/development/2018-07-21-ecology.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Celeste Initial Impressions</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/game-reviews/2018-01-26-celeste-initial-impressions.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>Celeste Initial Impressions</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> TL;DR - It looks pretty good so far, play it!
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2018-01-26" pubdate data-updated="true">January 26, 2018</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 3 mins
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/game-reviews.html">game-reviews</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/tags/celeste.html">celeste</a>, <a href="/tags/matt%20thorson.html">matt thorson</a>, <a href="/tags/initial%20impressions.html">initial impressions</a>, <a href="/tags/indie%20games.html">indie games</a>
</div>


<p><img src="/images/celeste/boxart-final3.png" /></p>
<p>Celeste became available on the Nintendo Switch last night and I swooped in on my copy!</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>I want to both:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Finish this game, and</li>
<li>Get around to writing up what I learnt from it.</li>
</ol>
<p>However in both cases, it is highly likely that I will either:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Never get around to it, or</li>
<li>Get around to it at a much later date.</li>
</ol>
<p>I really hope that I don’t let <code>1.</code> happen in either case, as my first play session with it left me feeling that it is:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>A really fun game, and</li>
<li>There is so much to learn from it in terms of creating a deep rewarding gameplay experience with a simple gameplay mechanic supported by brilliant level design.</li>
</ol>
<p>In any case, just in case either of those two scenarios eventuates, I want to take a brief note of my initial impression from the first play session. That way if I take longer than I expect to do a full write up, I have some notes of what I thought initially so I can remark on how my opinion changed or how it delivered on this initial promise. If I never get around to finishing it or doing a write up, then at least I wrote something on it.</p>
<h2 id="initial-impressions">Initial Impressions</h2>
<p>Just some dot points:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hQC0wNj6jNw">For some reason</a> I have this impression that Thorson’s game design style displays a certain diabolical cunning that players will find quite punishing.
<ul>
<li>As a (crap) platformer player, I tend to avoid platformers on this extreme end of the spectrum.</li>
<li>I never got around to buying or playing Super Meat Boy or Undertale for this reason.</li>
<li>I usually marvel at these games vicariously by watching speedruns for them.</li>
<li>Even from the beginning I found some of the rooms quite challenging, hopefully for me the difficulty doesn’t ramp up too much more…</li>
<li>However, Celeste seems very self aware that it will be punishing in terms of the demands on the players timing and dexterity. To that end it seems to balance it out with a strong measure of forgiveness:
<ul>
<li>You have infinite lives</li>
<li>There is no requirement beyond “getting through the puzzles that are put in front of you”.
<ul>
<li>Collectable strawberries are purely optional.</li>
<li>Collecting and playing through B-Sides are optional.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Each level is divided up into small room sized chunks that constitute self contained puzzles, when you die, you just go back to the beginning of that room.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Theres replayability for those who:
<ul>
<li>Like collecting stuff</li>
<li>Like more punishment in the form of the “B-Side” levels.</li>
<li>Research speedruns for games.
<ul>
<li>This game seems pretty ideal for speedrunners actually, the speedrun clock feature indicates that its been aimed at that demographic.</li>
<li>I’ll be looking forward to seeing speedruns for this at the various <a href="https://gamesdonequick.com/">Games Done Quick</a> events.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>I play more for plot, so I’ll likely be putting it down after</li>
</ul></li>
<li>In terms of what the player can do, the mechanics are fairly simple, you can climb and have this “dash” ability.
<ul>
<li>Its fairly easy to get used to controlling the player for this reason. Given that the puzzles will require good timing and mixed measure of foresight and improvisation, the simple mechanics and controls serve the player well in that regard.</li>
<li>The depth of the gameplay mechanics and level design come from the environmental gameplay mechanics, the moving platforms, the unstable platforms, the “pragmatic part” of Madeline, etc…
<ul>
<li>This provides a strong “explorational/discovery” theme for the game, similar to Mario Odyssey. But its a big promise to have to deliver on. Mario Odyssey ended up feeling a little stale for me towards the end when they stopped delivering “new experiences” by way of new NPCs to control.</li>
<li>The environmental game play mechanics complement Madelines abilities very well.</li>
<li>I’ll be very impressed if Celeste manages to deliver this sensation of discovery all the way up to the end of the game.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>The plot seems promising in terms of charm and heart.
<ul>
<li>The team behind it had a very nice coherent idea of the themes the game would be about.
<ul>
<li>That is: Exploration and Discovery (of your environment, and yourself).</li>
<li>I’ll see if it remains focussed for the duration of the whole game.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/game-reviews/2018-01-26-celeste-initial-impressions.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Micro Blogpost</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2018-01-08-rss-feed.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>Micro Blogpost</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> We have an RSS Feed
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2018-01-08" pubdate data-updated="true">January  8, 2018</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 1 min
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/news.html">news</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/tags/rss.html">rss</a>
</div>


<p>We have an <a href="http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/rss.xml">RSS feed</a> now.</p>
<p>Its a little old fashioned compared to Twitter, and even Atom Feeds, but whatever, its just what I use.</p>
<p>That is all.</p>
<!-- more -->
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2018-01-08-rss-feed.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>I am Still Here</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/musings/2018-01-05-I-am-still-here.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>I am Still Here</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> My goal to blog more
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2018-01-05" pubdate data-updated="true">January  5, 2018</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 2 mins
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/musings.html">musings</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> 
</div>


<p>Yeah, I am still here</p>
<!-- more -->
<h2 id="reflections">Reflections</h2>
<p>I haven’t really posted as much here as I have wanted to.</p>
<p>Reflecting upon it, I feel it ultimately boils down to the fact that this is currently a part time enterprise.</p>
<p>Progress is slow.</p>
<p>Like really slow.</p>
<p>So quantity wise I don’t really perceive much has happened to talk about.</p>
<p>Naturally on top of that there is then the question of “what little there is that has happened, how much of it is post worthy”.</p>
<p>Looking back on my notes, it seems my answer to that question is consistently “not much”.</p>
<h2 id="turning-it-around">Turning it Around</h2>
<p>However I do really want to get in the habit of posting here more frequently, for engagement, but also for practical purposes.</p>
<p>I feel in my “old” age if I don’t write down my strongly held opinions I end up forgetting them!</p>
<p>It also helps with the really strong sense of isolation you go through as an indie developer.</p>
<p>So I suppose I intend to combat the “quantity” problem by increasing the scope of the subject matter.</p>
<p>For the last few months, Irreverent Pixel Feats has been engaged in providing consulting services for “end-to-end tech business”. What I mean is we has provided consulting services that treat tech business as an “end to end” undertaking with the stakeholders and customers at one end and actual individuals as employees at the other end, with a slightly more specific focus on the employees tasked with actually making the whims of the stakeholders and customers a reality. You could paraphrase it as “concept” at one end and “reality” at the other. However that wording has lost its meaning these days as it does seem to ignore the actual humans involved and is more concerned with really high level strategy. In effect this ignores a major component of the “reality” end.</p>
<p>Basically we provide consulting on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tech Leadership</li>
<li>Tech Culture
<ul>
<li>With a practical analysis on actual human interactions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Architecture Design</li>
<li>Tooling</li>
<li>Software Development methodologies</li>
<li>Coding practices</li>
<li>etc…</li>
</ul>
<p>And we look at it all through the lens of Philosophy, Mathematics, Psychology, etc…</p>
<p>So thats what I mean, its pretty broad. But so far the benefit of the effort has been that all these things become consistent, self-reinforcing, with a more even distribution of satisfied interests after the high level picture has been proposed by one person.</p>
<p>I don’t really want to go into the specifics of what that entails or any examples.</p>
<p>However, in the interest of increasing the “quantity” of material I am considering for posts, I want to enlarge the scope of the blog to include said specifics and examples.</p>
<p>But IPF, especially with the addition of this consultancy side venture have provided me with a massive learning experience with the freedom to try new ideas, and to try them at scale.</p>
<p>In the future, this venture may get separated entirely from IPF into a separate entity, at which point I’ll move the related content over to the relevent place.</p>
<p>But the most important thing for me right now is to just start writing stuff.</p>
<p>As for the quality concern, looking back on my notes in retrospect I feel this is more based on fear on my part.</p>
<p>So I guess I’ll just try and be more conscious of “taking the leap”.</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/musings/2018-01-05-I-am-still-here.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AdventureX 2017</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2017-11-11-adventurex-2017.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>AdventureX 2017</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> AdventureX 2017 starts today!
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2017-11-11" pubdate data-updated="true">November 11, 2017</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 4 min
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/news.html">news</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/tags/adventurex.html">adventurex</a>, <a href="/tags/adv2017.html">adv2017</a>, <a href="/tags/adventurex2017.html">adventurex2017</a>
</div>


<p><img src="/images/AdventureX2017/KS-Image-750x500.jpg" /></p>
<p><a href="https://adventurexpo.org/">AdventureX 2017</a> starts today (and finishes tomorrow, November 12)!</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>We’re very proud to be among the sponsors for <a href="https://adventurexpo.org/">AdventureX 2017</a>!</p>
<p>AdventureX is an expo dedicated entirely to narrative driven games, there are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Talks that are educational for both game developers (in particular indie game developers) and gamers interested narrative driven games.</li>
<li>AdventureX also provides a floor for indies to exhibit their games to gamers.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s been going since 2011 (I think).</p>
<p>They manage to attract well accomplished talent to speak about their craft, this year they have got:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/WadjetEyeGames">Dave Gilbert</a> (Wadjet Eye Games, The Blackwell Series)</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/GrundislavGames">Francisco Gonzalez</a> (Shardlight, A Golden Wake)</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/tronbevan">Lottie Bevan</a> (Fail Better Games, Fallen London, Sunless Sea, Sunless Skies)</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/joningold">Jon Ingold</a> (<a href="https://inklestudios.com">inkle Studios</a>, 80 days, Sorcery!)</li>
<li><a href="http://users.wpi.edu/~bmoriarty/">Brian Moriarty</a> (Loom)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.adventurexpo.org/schedule/">And many more…</a> (This sampling doesn’t really do justice to the diversity of the speakers they have managed to wrangle)</li>
</ul>
<p>(This year) They livestream the talks.</p>
<p><em>And they do all this without charging for entry</em>.</p>
<p>So again, we’re very proud to be among the sponsors for this event.</p>
<p>It is one of our aspirations to count ourselves as part of the supportive community that AdventureX nurtures and makes so accessible to the masses.</p>
<p>Until we actually have a title or two in the can, however, we’ll have to make do with throwing over some money.</p>
<p>A big thanks goes out to the organisers of this event, and congratulations to <a href="http://www.adventurexpo.org/#projects">all the exhibitors</a>.</p>
<h2 id="some-of-our-favourite-talks-from-2016">Some of our Favourite Talks from 2016</h2>
<iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTJHPPlqC9c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
<iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bx5ZLGBZAWs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
<iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OeXxjabTl3g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
<iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5oLD2cD9a_Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
<p>Theres a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5oLD2cD9a_Y&amp;list=PLCsMVt0zsko1fbal17lqmAXZ2n_iFhTyd">more complete YouTube playlist here</a></p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2017-11-11-adventurex-2017.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Land of No</title>
    <link>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2017-05-31-land-of-no.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Land of No</h1>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"/> Our first post!
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"/> <time datetime="2017-05-31" pubdate data-updated="true">May 31, 2017</time>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-user-circle" aria-hidden="true"/> Dom De Re
</div>



<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"/> 1 min
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-folder" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/categories/news.html">news</a>
</div>


<div class="info">
    <i class="fa fa-bookmark" aria-hidden="true"/> <a href="/tags/land-of-no.html">land-of-no</a>
</div>


<p>We have arrived to take our stab at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u9P20Jskwmo" title="Bob Bates talking about leading a creative life in the land of no at GDC 2016">leading a creative life in the land of no</a>!</p>
<p>The blog isn’t much to look at now, but its a work in progress, and we just wanted to get something up.</p>
<p>You can take a look at <a href="/philosophy.html">our philosophy</a> to get the long spiel of what we are about.</p>
<p>The <code>TL;DR</code> is that we want to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create narrative driven games the way we want to</li>
<li>Apply Functional Programming to game development</li>
<li>Learn from the rest of the game development community</li>
<li>Give back to the game community</li>
</ul>
<!-- more -->
<p>Now is a hard and exciting time to be an indie game developer.</p>
<p>We will look to post often about our experiences as we find our feet.</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://irreverentpixelfeats.com/posts/news/2017-05-31-land-of-no.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Dom De Re</dc:creator>
</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
